https://www.pelicanparts.com/support/privacy_popup.htm

Pelican Parts, LLC - Privacy Policy
Last Updated: January 6th, 2020
Your privacy is important to Pelican Parts, LLC (“Company”, “we”, “us”). This
privacy policy (“Policy”) explains how Company collects, uses, and discloses
information through its websites, platform, mobile applications and other
online services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Services”)
or otherwise interact with us. If you obtain your use of the Services in
connection with the services offered by a third party, the individual terms of
that third party’s contract with us and its own privacy policy may differ from
what is described in this Policy.
Changes to This PolicyWe may change this Policy from time to time. If
we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the “last updated” date
above. If there are material changes to this Policy and you have an active
account with us, we will notify you more directly. We encourage you to check
this Policy whenever you use any of Services to understand how your personal
information is used.
Information CollectedWe collect information from you in various ways
when you use our Services. We may also supplement this information with
information from other companies. We collect two general types of information:
personal information and aggregate data. As used in this Policy, the term
“personal information” means information that specifically identifies an
individual (such as a name and email address), and demographic and other
information when directly linked to information that can identify an
individual.
Our definition of personal information does not include “aggregate data”.
Aggregate data is information we collect about a group or category of services
or users from which individual user identities have been removed. In other
words, no personal information is included in aggregate data. Aggregate data
helps us understand trends in our users’ needs so that we can better consider
new features or otherwise tailor our Services.
The following are the specific types of information we collect from you:
Information You Give Us. We collect information you give through our
Services, and when you register for and use our Services. Examples include the
following:
Registration and Contact Information. When you register to use
our Services or update your profile, we may collect various kinds of
information about you including, your name and email address; shipping
address; company name, company title, and other profile information you
provide; demographic information; and information you upload like photos.
Device and Activity Information. When you use your mobile device
with the Services, data recorded on your mobile device about your activity is
transferred from your mobile device to our servers. This data is stored and
used to provide the Service and is associated with your account. We also
collect information about any rehabilitee protocols you may be using.
Payment and Shipping Information. If you choose to order a product
through the Services, our payment processing vendor collects your payment card
information and billing address, and your shipping address and other contact
details, such as email address and phone number, may also be collected.Submissions and Company Services.
From time to time we may use surveys, contests or sweepstakes requesting
personal or demographic information and customer feedback. If you choose to
order a product through the Services, you may post a Product review.
Automatically Collected Information. We automatically receive certain
types of information when you interact with our Services. For example, it is
standard for your web browser to automatically send information to every web
site you visit, including ours. That information includes your computer’s IP
address, access times, your browser type and language, and referring web site
addresses. We may also collect information about the type of operating system
you use, your account activity, and files and pages accessed or used by you.
Cookies and Web Beacons. We may also use certain kinds of technology
such as cookies and web beacons to collect information. Among other things, the
use of cookies and web beacons enables us to improve our Services and emails by
seeing which areas and features are most popular, to count the number of
computers accessing our web site, to personalize and improve your experience,
to record your preferences, and to allow you to visit our Services without
re-entering your member ID and/or password. A cookie is a small amount of data
which is sent to your browser from a web site’s computers and stored on your
computer’s hard drive. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the
default setting. You can modify your browser setting to reject our cookies or
to prompt you before accepting a cookie by editing your browser options.
However, if a browser is set not to accept cookies or if a user rejects a
cookie, some portions of the web site and services may not function properly.
For example, you may not be able to sign in and access certain web page
features or services. A web beacon is an electronic image, also called a "gif,"
that may be used on our web pages to deliver cookies, count visits and compile
statistics on usage and campaign effectiveness or in our emails to tell if an
email has been opened and acted upon. For more information about cookies and
how to disable them, please see "Choices/Opt-Out" below.
Use of Personal Information
In general, we use your personal information to process your requests or
transactions, to provide you with information or services you request, to
inform you about other information, events, promotions, products or services we
think will be of interest to you, to facilitate your use of, and our
administration and operation of, the Services and to otherwise serve you and
our users. For example, we may use your personal information:
to enable you to conduct commercial transactions on the Site;
to send you a welcoming email and to contact you about your use of the
Services; to respond to your emails, submissions, comments, requests or
complaints; to perform after-sales services; to anticipate and resolve
problems with our service; to respond to customer support inquiries, for
assistance with our product and service development; and to inform you of
updates to products and services from Company that better meet your needs;
to enable you to post submissions on the Site and for you to communicate
with other users of the Site;
to request feedback and to enable us to develop, customize and improve our
Services;
to conduct marketing analysis, to send you surveys or newsletters, to
contact you about services, products, activities, special events or offers
from Company or our partners and for other marketing, informational, product
development and promotional purposes;
to contact you if you win a contest; and
for other purposes about which we notify you.
Sharing of Personal Information
We will not give, sell, rent, share, or trade any of your personal information
with any third party except as outlined in this Policy or with your consent. We
may disclose personal information:
To a third party to provide the Services to you, including by providing
personal information to our third party payment processors, to original
equipment manufacturers of products you order from the Site, and other third
party vendors or service providers that have contracted with us to provide the
Services to you who need access to such information to carry out work on our
behalf and who may use personal information to improve their services;
With select partners who provide fraud detection and prevention services to
us;
To a third party to comply with laws or respond to lawful requests and
legal process, including national security requirements;
To a third party to protect Company, agents, customers, and others
including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use;
To a third party in the good faith belief that disclosure is needed to
respond to an emergency, or protect the personal safety of any person;
To a third party in connection with an acquisition, merger, or sale of all
or a substantial portion of our business, with or to another company. In such
an event, you will receive notice if your data is transferred and becomes
subject to a substantially different privacy policy;
Between and among Company and our current and future parents, affiliates,
subsidiaries and other companies under common control and ownership;
To third parties, including advertising agencies, for providing marketing
to you via targeted advertisements on third party websites and email marketing;
and
To third parties to provide contest and sweepstakes to you.
The Services may include features that by their nature support sharing your
content (i.e., photos, videos, text) that you upload or post on the Services in
a public forum, such as a discussion forum or product reviews. Other users of
the Services can see personal information you choose to share, such as your
location, interests, occupation and birthday; and they can post comments in
response to certain of your public submissions.
This Policy in no way restricts or limits our collection and use of aggregate
data, and we may share aggregate data about you and our users with third
parties for various purposes in perpetuity, including to help us better
understand our customer needs and improve our Services, to provide new Services
and for advertising and marketing purposes.
Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others.
We may allow others to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the internet and in applications.
These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites and applications, including your IP address, web browser, mobile network information, pages viewed, time spent on pages or in apps, links clicked and conversion information.
This information may be used by Company and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and better understand your online activity.
For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit
www.aboutads.info/choices.
Network and Information Security
We take reasonable steps to protect information we collect from you to prevent
loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.
The servers on which information is stored are kept in a controlled environment
with limited access. While we take reasonable efforts to guard personal
information we knowingly collect directly from you, no security system is
impenetrable. In addition, we cannot guarantee that any collected personal
information you choose to include in the Services are maintained at adequate
levels of protection to meet specific needs or obligations you may have
relating to that information.
Data Retention
We store the information we collect about you for as long as is necessary for
the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may retain certain
information for legitimate business purposes or as required by law.
Data Transfers
To provide the Services, we may transfer your information to our servers in the
United States or other countries. When we transfer information from the
European Economic Area ("EEA") to countries that have not been deemed to
provide an adequate level of protection, we employ data processing agreements
based on the Standard Contractual Clauses to help ensure that your data is
protected wherever it is transferred. You may request a copy of these clauses
by contacting us by one of the methods listed at
https://www.pelicanparts.com/support/ContactUs.htm
When we transfer personal data from the European Union or Switzerland to the United States, we comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss - U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. We have certified to the Department of Commerce that we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.
In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, we are committed to resolving complaints about our processing of your personal data. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our compliance with the Privacy Shield program should first contact us. We have further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to the International Centre for Dispute Resolution - American Arbitration Association, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html for more information or to file a complaint. The services of the International Centre for Dispute Resolution - American Arbitration Association are provided at no cost to you.
Under certain conditions, you may be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint. Company is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission.
If we share personal data transferred to the U.S. under the Privacy Shield with a third-party service provider that processes such data on our behalf, then we will be liable for that third party’s processing in violation of the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we can prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage
Updating and Accessing Personal Information
If your personal information changes in any way, you must correct or update
your information in order to place orders for products through the Services.
You can make updates to your profile information by logging into your account
on the Services at any time to the extent such feature is available. You can
also request changes or access to your information by contacting us by one of
the methods listed at
https://www.pelicanparts.com/support/ContactUs.htm
Choice/Opt-Out
Company may send you communications or data regarding our Services, including
but not limited to (i) notices about your use of our Services, including any
notices concerning violations of use, (ii) updates, and (iii) promotional
information and materials regarding our Services. You may opt-out of receiving
promotional emails from Company by following the opt-out instructions provided
in those emails. You may also opt-out of receiving promotional emails and other
promotional communications from us at any time by contacting us by one of the
methods listed at
https://www.pelicanparts.com/support/ContactUs.htm with your specific
request. Opt-out requests will not apply to transactional service messages,
such as security alerts and notices about your current account and Services. We
also use cookies for various purposes. Most web browsers are set to accept
cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser
to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove
or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our
Services. Additionally, if you are a resident of the European Economic Area,
you may exercise certain rights over your data, as described in the Data
Subject Requests section below.
Residents of the European Economic Area
If you are a resident of the EEA, you have certain rights and protections under
the law regarding the processing of your personal data.
Legal Basis for Processing
If you are a resident of the EEA, when we process your personal data, we will
only do so under the following circumstances:
In order to perform our responsibilities under a contract with our customers,
such as by providing the Services you requested; or
We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data, such as to
send you communications about products or services that may interest you.
Data Subject Requests
If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the right to access personal data we
hold about you and to ask that your personal data be corrected, erased, or
transferred. You may also have the right to object to, or request that we
restrict, certain processing, for example, sharing your data with certain third
parties. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, you should contact
your employer who uses our services. You may also contact us using the contact
information below to exercise these rights, but be advised that we generally do
not retain the personal data we collect to identify the customer experiences
you are eligible to access, and thus will likely not be able to honor your
request.
Questions or Complaints
If you are a resident of the EEA and have a concern about our processing of
personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a
complaint with the data privacy authority where you reside. For contact details
of your local Data Protection Authority, please see:
http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm.
Contacting Us.
Any questions about this Policy should be addressed to legal@pelicanparts.com
